Hello Hello
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте
from Ukraine, the city of Khmelnitsky And where are you
из Украины город Хмельницкий А вы откуда
from Russia
из России
Saratov Saratov support the special operation
Саратов Саратов спецоперацию
in general Yes, you have someone fighting in Ukraine
в целом да у вас кто-то воюет на Украине
so adults
так взрослые
nobody as usual if I meet
никто как обычно если вот я встречаю
women who are sitting on a roulette wheel holding
женщин которые сидят рулетке держит
special operations usually they have one of their
спецоперации обычно у них кто-то из
friends or  relatives will you
знакомых или родственников будет вы
have been mobilized no at the moment
приняли мобилизированы нет данный момент
And what brought you to chat
А что вас привело в чат рулетку
roulette I seem to have the whole world standing by the
у меня как бы весь мир стоит
current situation What is the current
текущая обстановка Какая на текущая
situation please tell us the
обстановка поведайте пожалуйста
current situation in the world in the country that with
текущая обстановка в мире в стране что с
this situation that it is necessary to attack
этой обстановкой что надо напасть на
Ukraine I can’t explain
Украину объяснить не могу понять
you  you don’t understand, yes
вы не понимаете да
Well, you can see it’s so advanced I don’t
Ну вот такой видно продвинутый Я не
quite I don’t understand why Russia
совсем Я не понимаю почему Россия напала
attacked Ukraine people still support it in
на Украине люди еще это поддерживает в
Russia, you can explain your opinion
России можете объяснить свое мнение
why you, as a citizen of Russia,
почему вы Как гражданка России
support this war
поддержите эту войну
Well, because this is not a war, but a
Ну потому что это не война а
special operation
спецоперация
Why support a special operation
Почему поддержки спецоперацию
Because  if the
Потому что если
operation should say thank you Well, yes,
операцию должны спасибо сказать Ну да
because Putin fights  tsya call it a
потому что Путин боится это назвать
war because he will declare war on us
войной потому что он объявит войну нам
americans
американцы
bomb Moscow and saratov
бомбить Москву и Саратов
bombing
бомбардировку
4 february ukraine according to
4 февраля Украина по словам России
russia bombed Donetsk russia decided to protect
Бомбила Донецк Россия решила защитить
Donetsk now we are bombing belgorod and
Донецка Теперь мы бомбим Белгород и
russia can’t protect belgorod
Россия не может защитить Белгород
as a result of
в результате
acid we first just bombed the
кислоте Мы сначала просто так бомбили
residential areas of Donetsk a  now it
жилые кварталы Донецка А теперь нам
has become interesting for us we are bombing residential areas of
стало интересен мы бомбим жилые кварталы
Belgorod and Putin can’t
Белгорода а Путин ничего не может
do anything why
сделать почему так
so why are you bombing the stomach we are such
а зачем вы бомбите живот мы такие
Nazi fascists We first Yes no
фашисты нацисты Мы сначала Да нет мы
we bombed our own And now we decided to
своих бомбили А теперь решили нам своих
bomb a few of ours Let’s Belgorod
мало бомби Давайте Белгород
I don’t know why Zelensky Why is he
вот не знаю почему Зеленский Для чего он
I would like to have Belgorod I would like
бы имеет Белгород Я хотел бы чтобы
Saratov to be bombed and Moscow about the Kremlin
Саратов по бомбили и Москву про Кремль
really, I really wanted
реально я вот хотел
There nearby
Там рядом
[laughter]
[смех]
and in Engels for civilians a mobile
а в Энгельсе по мирным жителям мобиль
airfield How do you say
аэродром Как вы скажете
on the airfield
по аэродрому
that Bombed Peaceful Donetsk in
которая Бомбила Мирный Донецк свой в
your Engels hit the airfield and
Энгельсе вашем ударила по аэродрому а не
not  peaceful Why so
по мирным Почему так
because Engels is still far given
потому что Энгельс все-таки далеко дано
Yes well Yes why For example our low  Oh,
Да ну Да почему Например наши низкая А
let's go to Angels, they had a nine-story building
давайте мы в ангельсе там девятиэтажку
Why, then why is it Ukraine,
Зачем так зачем тогда получается Украина
I understand correctly Ukraine just its own
я правильно понимаю Украина просто свой
Donetsk Bombed for 8 years
Донецк Бомбила 8 лет
Yes, Angels does not want
Да ангельс не хочет
Yes, Angels does not want the airfield Donetsk
да ангельс не хочет аэродром Донецк
Bombed people and in Engels there was an airfield
Бомбила людей а в Энгельсе аэродром
for some reason
почему-то
Well, because there was  one drone
Ну потому что там был один беспилотник
one he had a different target, but
один у него была другая цель но
for some reason he didn’t say on the New Year’s tree, we
почему-то не сказал в елку новогоднюю
’ll hit the pilot in Saratov, he’s the only one
ударимся в Саратове пилотник он один
Why, for example, Zelensky, look,
Почему например да Зеленский смотрите мы
we bombed our simple people with hailstones in
вот бомбили наших просто людей градами в
Donetsk, revere him in Engels,
Донецке отвами в Энгельсе ему залужник
let’s hit the Asian droma, no Come on,
Давай ударим дрому азиатских нет Давай
maybe here  A Christmas tree so that
может вот Елка чтобы собрались люди
mature people gather, we will hit the Christmas trees why he
вызрелки мы по елки ударим почему вот он
didn’t do this Why we kill civilians in Donetsk But we do
так не сделал Почему в Донецке мы
n’t kill civilians in Engels
убиваем мирных А в Энгельсе не убиваем
I answered your question Well,
Я же вам ответил на ваш вопрос Ну как
as we had one drone Why we
вот у нас был один беспилотник Почему мы
will be in Engels we didn’t kill there
будем в Энгельсе не убили там
Why  we go to school Why didn't we
Почему мы в школу Почему мы в школу не
hit the school in Engels hit the airfield
ударили в Энгельсе ударили в аэродром
Why did Zelensky choose the target the airfield in
Почему Зеленский выбрал цель аэродром в
Donetsk he chose the target civilians  ate And
Донецке он выбирал цель мирные жители А
in Engels they chose an airfield, they chose a school
в Энгельсе выбрал аэродром они школу
Then why did we release hailstones like in
Тогда зачем мы выпускали грады типа в
Donetsk not at your troops somehow
Донецке не по вашим войскам каким-то так
But at people just And in Engels they decided to
А по людям просто А в Энгельсе решили
hit the troops Why so
ударить по войскам Почему так
Well, because there are no bombers in Donetsk
Ну потому что в Донецке нету
And what happened, that is, in
бомбардировщиков А что было то есть в
There is no Russian army in Donetsk, so there is none at all And then I have a second question, look if the Ukrainian army could not drive out the Russian mouse there, we understand that there are no Russian troops in Donetsk Lugansk There were just some miners with
Там просто стояли какие-то шахтеры с
sticks Yes, and the Ukrainian army could
палками Да и украинской армии их не
not drive them out for 8 years  but at the same time, the
могла выгнать 8 лет но при этом из
Ukrainian army of the 30,000-strong
Херсона украинская армия 30тысячную
Russian group was able to force the Ukrainian army from Kherson to
российскую группировку смогла заставить
leave somehow from Kherson without shelling
уйти как-то из Херсона не обстреляв
Kherson, though it
Херсон правда
’s so funny, yes, I’ll be funny,
вот такой смешной да будет я смешной
I’m really laughing at why the
реально я смеюсь того что почему
huge Ukrainian army was able to drive out the
украинская армия огромная смогла выгнать
Russian 30-thousandth group of a
российскую 30-тысячную группировку
professional personnel army with
профессиональной кадровой армии с
aviation  with tanks from Kherson, but could
авиацией с танками так из Херсона но не
not expel some Miners with sticks
смогла каких-то Шахтеров с палками
from Donetsk Why is that
выгнать из Донецка Почему так
what let
какой давайте
me answer your question you answer
я ответил на ваш вопрос Вы ответите на
mine you ran away from questions why
мой вы убежали от вопросов Почему
I
я
can’t understand the riddle
не могу понять загадку
let’s answer well let’s answer let’s
Давайте хорошо ответьте Давайте ответим
answer answer you shout at me everything
Давай ответь ответь вы мне перекрики всё
I’m silent answer really no you
я молчу отвечайте правда нет вы вот
now it’s not a secret to anyone that here
сейчас вот никому не секрет что вот вот
for yesterday  On the 31st, Russia of the Russian
на вчера 31 числа Россия Российской
Federation delivered a series of strikes on Ukraine, it
Федерации наносила ряд ударов по Украине
was such
был такой
in different places there, in response, I don’t
по разным там местам вот в ответ ну не
know, in response, not in response, but yesterday, on the
знаю в ответ не в ответ но вчера вот 31
31st, on the night of the low,
числа в ночь куда низкую было выпущено
a lot of Ukrainian missiles were fired that
очень много украинских ракет которые
hit
попали
equipment in the hospital residential areas you
технику в больнице жилые кварталы вы
bomb residential quarters quarters of your own
бомбите жилые квартале кварталы своих
people you think that Donetsk is
людей своих вы считаете что Донецк это
Ukraine question Why are you killing your
Украина вопрос Почему вы убиваете своих
people I also can’t understand it look
людей я тоже не могу это понять смотрите
I ask questions
Я задаю вопросы
if Ukraine is so cool that it was able to
если Украина настолько крутая что смогла
recapture the Russian personnel army
отвоевать российской кадровой армии
Kherson where there were 30 thousand
Херсон где было 30 тысяч
soldiers so aviation tanks then why
солдат так авиация танки то почему
just go to Donetsk and pick up Donetsk
просто зайти в Донецк и забрать Донецк
some miners with sticks, she
каких-то Шахтеров с палками она его
fired at him, what a joke I can’t  it’s
обстрели в чем прикол не могу понять
easy to understand why she didn’t take Donetsk away
почему она не забрала Донецк просто
Well, first of all, our people just
Ну во-первых с Херсона люди наши просто
left Kherson. Yes,
Вышли да
inside yours left Kherson 30 thousand
внутри ваши вышли из Херсона 30 тысяч
left and in Donetsk there weren’t any of you at all,
вышли а в Донецке ваших вообще не было
which prevented ours from entering Donetsk just
что мешало нашим зайти в Донецк просто
like they entered Kherson because ours
как зашли в Херсон потому что наша
didn’t leave from there  but it’s not like yours were in
оттуда не вышли но это не то ваши были в
Donetsk, they don’t stand in the city itself
Донецке они не стоят в самом городе
Russian troops in the Donetsk region
российские войска в Донецкой области
have been since the age of 14 it wasn’t so if it wasn’t
были с 14 года не было так если не было
there Who prevented the Ukrainian troops from entering
то Кто мешал украинским войскам зайти в
Donetsk
Донецк
there were their own what they had their planes
там свои были чем они у них самолеты
tanks were what they had
танки были что у них
if some Ukrainians fought there what
если там воевали какие-то украинцы чем
they fought they had planes tanks
они воевали у них были самолеты танки
Ukraine had these people in Donetsk
Украине была у этих людей в Донецке
where they had tanks planes if
откуда у них были танки самолёты если
they just if they were not there they
они просто если там не было них было у
had a trench here they just
них было окопное вот это вот они просто
sat in the trenches against  tanks Yes, and they
в окопах сидели против танков Да и
threw stones at Tanks Yes,
камнями кидали в Танки Да
where did people get these weapons from
откуда это оружие взяли
somewhere they got weapons just that
люди где-то взяли оружие просто что 8
they had been fighting for 8 years against such a cool army
лет им воевать против такой крутой армии
and
и
about the Minsk agreements in general,
про минские соглашения вообще
here is Chita 2014, the
вот Чита 2014 год
Minsk agreements are under  wait for the fourteenth
минские соглашения подожди четырнадцатый
year where did these people get weapons from
год откуда у этих людей взялась оружие
if there
если там
look let me these people took weapons And
смотри давайте я эти люди взяли оружие А
where did they get weapons how could they get them
где они взяли оружие как они могли взять
Where did they
Откуда они взяли оружие
get weapons to take weapons weapons were not there
взять оружие оружие не было там
wonderful Ukraine why they did not take
чудесной Украине зачем они не брали
weapons there were no weapons where they came from
оружие не было там оружие откуда они
they could take it if Russia is not there
могли взять если Россия там нет
you said that the Russian army was not
вы сказали что Российская армии там не
there Look here, just a dude sits,
было Вот смотрите вот сидит просто чувак
look here, he sits asking where they
смотрите вот сидит спрашиваю откуда они
came from
взялись
Why did they take him from where they didn’t
Почему они его взяли откуда они у них не
have weapons they were unarmed I these
было оружия они безружные я эти 8 лет
8 years they were unarmed for 8 years
они 8 лет безружные были
look  I’m asking you why where they were
смотрите Я вас спрашиваю зачем где
forced where they took weapons I don’t understand
вынуждены где взяли оружие я не понимаю
Look here I’m just looking Here I’m a
Вот смотрите Я просто смотрю Вот я
simple programmer So surname where
простой программист Так фамилийском где
can I take weapons if a simple
я могу взять оружие если простой
programmer Donetsk or Shakhtar where he
программист Донецкий или Шахтер где он
could take weapons I didn’t ask you about this now
мог взять оружие Я вас сейчас не об этом
see if yes So  here you are
спрашивали смотрите если да Так вот вы
running away from the answer you are running away from the answer
убегаете от ответа вы убегайте от ответа
I say that there were no weapons there and no
Я говорю что там не было оружие и никто
one fought Look, I say that they did not
не воевал Смотри я говорю что они не
do there  the Russian army fought
делали там воевала российской армия
because the weapons were all Russian,
потому что оружие было все российское
too, yes If if you say that these are not
тоже да Если если вы говорите что это не
Russian weapons And where did they get the weapon,
российское оружие А где они взяли оружие
why did they take it where to understand
зачем они его брали где чтобы понять
why it is necessary to understand where they
зачем надо понять где
dug in the garden where they got it
выкопали в огороде где они взяли
I have a question Why is your country
У меня вопрос Почему ваша же страна
fighting
воюет против ваших
they were against yours, I, too, yes, I don’t understand, I don’t
они были я тоже да я не понимаю Я не
understand, I have a friend from Donetsk,
понимаю у меня есть знакомый из Донецка
that’s what they say Listen to you,
так они говорят Слушай вас там нормально
everything is fine there, yes, I have friends from Donetsk,
всё да у меня стоит знакомые из Донецка
they don’t speak Listen Andrey, we have been
не говорит Слушай Андрей мы 8 лет против
fighting against your country for 8 years Without weapons, as we
вашей страны Без оружия воюем так как мы
how could we take weapons if
могли как мы могли взять оружие если
Russia didn’t come to us where they got their
Россия к нам не приходило откуда у них
weapons from
оружие
No I’m not Andrey Tell me where from
Нет я не Андрей Скажите откуда Откуда
Tell me where the weapons come from where
Скажите откуда оружие откуда оружие у
these people
этих людей
have weapons we just shot at civilians there were no
мы просто по мирным стреляли никаких там
people with weapons yes I allow
людей с оружием не было да разрешаю
Thank you please I don’t have a question  in the answer
Спасибо пожалуйста я вопрос не в ответе
Let's tell me where these people got the
Давайте Скажите где эти люди взяли
weapons we'll go further
оружие мы пойдем дальше
why did they get
зачем они взяли
you burned out Because you understand that
ты подгорела Потому что ты понимаешь что
it's impossible that's where the people are in the sarator  in
невозможно вот в сараторе откуда люди в
Saratov they will take weapons they will not take them
Саратове возьмут оружие не возьмут
because
потому что
they were unarmed all eight years all
они были безружные все восемь лет все
unarmed we hit civilians if in
безружные мы били по мирным людям если в
Russia they gave weapons in the fourteenth year
России дала оружие в четырнадцатом году
Maybe they could push us back
Возможно они бы нас смогли оттеснить
come on why are they taken even if this
вот зачем где они взяли даже если вот
is a logical fork if Russian
это вилка до логическая если Российская
armies where they took weapons that they had been fighting for 8
армии где они взяли оружие что воевать 8
years Yes, literally in a month they
лет Да тут буквально за месяц это вот из
left Kherson because it was
Херсона ушли Потому что логистические
difficult to bring logistics and so on, but in Russia
сложно подвозить и так дальше а в России
and in Donetsk Lugan something for 8 years logistics
а в Донецке луган что-то 8 лет логистика
somehow everything was fine
как-то все было нормально